Guide to the New-York Historical Society Pictorial Archive 1804-2000 (bulk 1930-1960) NYHS 5
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society Pictorial Archive
1804-2000 (bulk 1930-1960)
NYHS 5
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
12.0 Linear feet (28 boxes)
The N-YHS Pictorial Archive spans the period from 1804-1988 (bulk dates 1930-1960) and contains photographs, sketches, and drawings relating to the history of the New-York Historical Society: its buildings, exhibits, programs, staff, and officers. Most of the collection consists of photographs. Portions of the collection have been digitized and can be viewed on flickr.
Scope and Content Note
The N-YHS Pictorial Archive spans the period from 1804-1988 (bulk dates 1930-1960) and contains photographs, sketches, posters and notices, architectural plans, and drawings relating to the history of the New-York Historical Society: its buildings, exhibits, programs, staff, and officers. Most of the collection consists of photographs; Series X includes architectural plans and drawings.
The photographs provide an overview of the cultural history of N-YHS and New York in this period, including changes in the buildings and the content of museum exhibits. The collection specifically includes many photographs of the construction of the Society's current home on Central Park West. Highlights of museum exhibit photgraphs include photos of women suffragists and Eleanor Roosevelt in the “Votes for Women” exhibit; and one of noted clown Emmett Kelly attending “Circus Posters from the Days of the Big Top.” Some of these images have been digitized and can be viewed on flickr.
Arrangement Note
The collection is arranged in ten series:
Series I: Buildings
Series II: Exhibits
Series III: School Programs
Series IV: Public Programs
Series V: Events
Series VI: Staff Events
Series VII: Staff
Series VIII: Directors and Trustees
Series IX: Museum Images
Series X: Architectural Plans and Drawings
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Historical Note
Timeline of Homes of N-YHS
1804-1809 The City Hall, Northside of Wall Street at the head of Broad Street
1809-1816 The Government House, Facing Bowling Green
1816-1832 New York Institution, in City Hall Park
1832-1837 Remsen Building, Southwest corner of Broadway at Chambers Street
1837-1841 Stuyvesant Institute, 639 Broadway opposite Bond Street
1841-1857 New York University, East Side of Washington Square
1857-1908 170 Second Avenue, Southeast corner of 11th Street
1908-present 170 Central Park West at 77th Street
History of N-YHS:
“For without the aid of historic records and authentic documents, history would be nothing more than a well-combined series of ingenious conjectures and amusing fables.” From an 1805 address of the New-York Historical Society
The New-York Historical Society is New York’s oldest museum. At the time of the Society’s founding in 1804, only 75,000 people lived in New York City, Alexander Hamilton had just been killed in a duel with Aaron Burr, and New York still spelled its name with a hyphen (thus the hyphen in the museum’s name). On November 20, 1804, merchant John Pintard met with ten other New Yorkers to create an organization that would, according to its Constitution, “collect and preserve whatever may relate to the natural, civil, or ecclesiastical History of the United States in general and of this State in particular.” This was a broad mission statement but since there were very few museums at the time, and only one other historical society in the nation, the founders decided it was imperative to collect an inclusive range of materials before they were lost.
The first meetings of the Society were held rent free in City Hall because New York City’s mayor, DeWitt Clinton, was a founding member. The Society’s library grew significantly in 1809 when Pintard sold his own book and manuscript collection to the New-York Historical Society. As the library and museum continued to grow, its members soon realized that it needed a home. Unable to find a permanent space, the Society moved five times between 1809 and 1857, until it was able to construct its own building on Second Avenue and Eleventh Street.
In the mid-19th century, the Society’s membership increased along with its library and art collections. Between 1858-1867, the Society acquired the collection of the New York Gallery of Fine Arts, the Abbott collection of Egyptian Artifacts (now at the Brooklyn Museum), and 433 watercolor paintings of John James Audubon. Soon the art and the library were competing for space and it became apparent that the Society had once again outgrown its home. In 1908, N-YHS moved into a newly constructed building at its present location at 77th Street and Central Park West. Renovations in the 1930’s added two new wings and a fifteen-story stack area to the building. Today, the museum and library continue to provide access to collections relating to the political, legal, cultural, mercantile, and social history of the United States and New York in particular.
For more detailed history see: Vail, R.W.G. Knickerbocker birthday: a sesqui-centennial history of the New York Historical Society, 1804-1954. New York: New York Historical Society, 1954.
Related Material
Other materials related to the history of N-YHS are located in the N-YHS Archives in the Manuscript Department.
- Series I: Buildings, 1804-1988
  Scope and Content
  This series documents the many homes of N-YHS. (See the above timeline for specific dates.) The series mostly depicts N-YHS in its homes on 2nd Avenue and the current home on Central Park West, as well as the Central Park West building construction.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Prints, drawings and plans, 1804-1866 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 170 Second Ave. (Exteriors), 1857-1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 170 Second Ave. (Interiors), 1857-1908 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 170 Second Ave. (Interiors), 1857-1908 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 170 Central Park West (Construction), 1903-1906 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 170 Central Park West (Construction), 1903-1905 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 170 Central Park West (Construction), 1905 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 170 Central Park West (Construction): Scrapbook, 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 170 Central Park West (Construction), 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 170 Central Park West (Exteriors), 1908-1937 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 170 Central Park West (Interiors), 1908-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 170 Central Park West, Annexes 1 and 2, 1926-1936 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 170 Central Park West, Construction of New Wing, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 170 Central Park West, Construction of New Wing, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 170 Central Park West, Construction of New Wing, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 170 Central Park West, Construction of New Wing, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 170 Central Park West, Construction of New Wing, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Thompson Homestead, Long Island, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Katherine Prentis Murphy Residence, Woodstock, Connecticut, circa 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 170 Central Park West, Exteriors, circa 1939-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 170 Central Park West, Exteriors, 1975 February (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 170 Central Park West, Exteriors, after 1937 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Library [1920-1982], 1920s-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Work areas, 1930s-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Galleries, 1930s-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Auditorium, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Galleries, 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Beekman Rooms, 1940-1947 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, War years, 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors/Exteriors, Anne Day, circa 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Port of NY Gallery, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 170 Central Park West, Interiors, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Exterior photographs, all buildings, Undated (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 1)
  - 170 Central Park West, interiors: mounted prints of reading room and galleries; floor plans for visitors, Undated (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 2)
  - Richard Morris Hunt: three designs for propsed historical museum (photoreproductions), 1866 (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 4)
  - 170 Second Avenue, interiors, undated (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 8)
  - 170 Central Park West, drawings and etchings, 1922, 1940, undated (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 9)
  - 170 Central Park West: photographs of cornerstone laying, Undated (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 13)
  - Architects York and Sawyer at future site of 170 Central Park West, Undated (Drawer 12A-10, Folder 15)
- Series II: Exhibits, 1932-2000
  The images in this series depict the various exhibitions that N-YHS held, mostly from the 1940's until the early 1990's. The titles of the folders are the titles of the exhibitions. Some oversized posters and notices are included at the end of the series.
  The exhibition materials are arranges chronologically and then by title of the exhibition.
  - First in Exhibits Ships and Steamboats/ Old New York, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - N-YHS 135th Anniversary, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - John Paul Jones/ Presidential Campaigns/ Emma Thursby, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Allied Artists Exhibitions, The NY Stage from the 1880’s, 1942 October (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Latin Americana, 1944 January (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - World of Washington Irving, 1944 October (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Wings Over the Central Pacific (Army Air Force), 1945 January (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jenny Lind, 1945 October (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Audubon Original Watercolors, 1946 January (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Historic Hudson/ Presentation Silver, 1946 October (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pictures by News Artists (H.T. Peters Collection), 1947 February (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Big Snows/ Doctors of Old New York, 1947 March (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Trinity Church 250th Anniversary/ Recent Accessions/ Frederic Remington Nov., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - American Quilts/ Gold Fever/ Up From the Cradle, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Bookplates (Sheean Collection)/ City Hall, 1949 October (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Gramercy Park, 1949 December (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Vernon Howe Bailey/ Erie Canal, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Steamboat and Railroad Prints/ Albert Gallatin, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Prentis Rooms, 1951 May (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - History in Manuscripts/ NYC Newspapers, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Recent Accessions/ 19th Century Children’s Books, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Early American Toys (Prentis Collection), 1951 December (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Manhattan Country Houses Built Before 1860, 1952 January (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 150th Anniversary of U.S. Military Academy (West Point), 1952 March (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sculptured Portraits by Malvina Hoffman, 1952 April (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Hats in the Ring, 1952 June (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Votes for Women, 1952 October (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Golden Anniversary of Greater NY, 1953 February (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Circus Time, 1953 April (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - The Healing Arts in Old New York, 1953 May (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Old-Fashioned Winters/ William Sidney Mount, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Early American Arts and Crafts, 1954 February (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Tom Thumb, 1954 March (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History of N-YHS/ 150th Anniversary Hamilton-Burr Duel, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Society’s Treasures/ IRT Subway 50th Anniversary, 1954 October (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Livingston Family/ 300th Anniversary Spanish and Portuguese Synagogue/ American Glass, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Bicentennial of Fort Ticonderoga/ IRT 50th Anniversary, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Shircliffe Menu Collection, 1955 October (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - NY: The Empire State/ Eat, Drink, and be Wary, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Presidential Campaign Cartoons, 1956 September (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - NY: City of Authors/ Three NYC Architects/ Mayors of New York, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Portraits of the Stuyvesants, 1958 April (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - America in Daguerreotypes/ Feminine Costume, 1958 October (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Rediscovered Painters of Upstate New York, 1959 February (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - The Hudson: River of History, 1959 April (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Niagara Falls 1678-1960/ Presidential Campaign of 1960 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - It Paid to Advertise/ A Nation Divided, 1861-1864/ New York: Host to the World, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - American Silhouette Portraits/ Manhattan Passenger Transportation/ Rare Books, 1962 March (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Audubon: Birds of America, 1963 October (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Colorful New Yorkiana/ New York Crystal Palace, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Treasures of the New-York Historical Society, 1964 May (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - New York City Views, 1800-1900, 1965 April (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - American Military Weapons/ Historic Hudson, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Glass Paperweights, 1966 April (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Merchants and Planters of the Upper Hudson Valley, 1700-1750, 1967 May (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Theatrical Posters of Bygone Days, 1880-1920/ A Visit from St. Nick, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Circus Posters from Days of the Big Top, 1968 March (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Circus Posters from Days of the Big Top, 1968 March (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Advertising Posters from the 19th Century/ Scrimshaw, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - A Decade of Collecting, 1959-1969, 1969 October (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Glass Paperweights, 1970 February (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - A Visitor Looks at America: Baroness Hyde de Neuville, 1970 March (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - New York Maritime City/ Eye on the City, The Photographer in New York 1840-1900, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - City of Promise: Aspects of Jewish Life in New York, 1654-1970, 1971 March (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - American Sculpture in Plaster, Wood, Metal, Stone/ John Rogers’ Household Gods, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Toy Installation/ The American Revolution, 1972 April (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Road to the White House, 1972 July (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Original Drawing for “Birds of America”, 1972 October (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Miniatures and Medals/ New York Nostalgia, 1973 January (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - The Duyckincks: Merchants, Chiefs and Painters, 1973 October (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - New York to 1765: River, Bowery, Mill, and Beaver, 1973 October (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Old New York in Early Photographs, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Be My Valentine, 1974 February (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Manhattan Now: 14 Photographers Look at the Form of the City, 1974 April (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - Manhattan Now: 14 Photographers Look at the Form of the City, 1974 April (Box 10, Folder 1-7)
  - Americans in Silhouette (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - New York in the New Empire: John Pintard and his Society, 1974 October (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - New York in the New Empire: John Pintard and his Society, 1974 October (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - New York in the New Empire: John Pintard and his Society, 1974 October (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Shaker Objects from the Collection of Edward Derning and Faith Andrews, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Shaker Objects from the Collection of Edward Derning and Faith Andrews – William Winter photos of New Lebanon NH, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New York in the Revolution/ Ain’t I a Woman?, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - America A La Carte, 1975 July (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - John Trumbull: Patriot Artist of the Revolution/ American Genre Paintings of 19th Century, 1975 October (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Glass Paperweights (reinstallation)/ Mount Pleasant Scale Model, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - The New York Cabinetmaker and His Use of Space, 1976 January (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The New York Cabinetmaker and His Use of Space, 1976 January (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Words and Music: Sheet Music of Not So Long Ago/ History at Home: Decorative Arts of the 18th and 19th Century, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Campaigns, Conventions and Candidates/Op Sail, 1976 June (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Selling New York (Landauer Collection)/ The Face of New York: Photographs of Andreas Feininger, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - The Dutch Republic in the Days of John Adams, 1775-1795, 1976 December (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Moving in the City: Three Centuries of Transportation, 1976 December (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Moving in the City: Three Centuries of Transportation, 1976 December (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Remember the Ladies: Women in America 1750-1815/ Jenny Lind in New York, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - New York Stock Exchange/ New York Fashions and Facades: Photographs by William Cunningham, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Think Small/ Give Me That Old Time Religion, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Street Kids, 1978 February (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Art of the Conservator/ Wish You Were Here, The American Magazine, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - World War I Posters, 1978 November (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - New York in the Forties: Photographs by Andreas Feininger, 1978 December (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Collecting for the Future: 25 Years of Acquisitions/ Revisiting the World’s Fair of 1939/ Artists and Architects of The New York Subway, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Knickerbocker Birthday/ Murder! Murder Most Foul, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - 55 Wall Street: A Working Landmark/ Tiffany Silver, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - That Belmont Look, 1980 January (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Panorama of Presidential Elections/ Dutch Scripture Painting/ Phrenology of the Land, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Drypoints of Mortimer Borne/ New York Art on the Move/ Small Folk: A Celebration of Childhood in America/ The White Mountains: Place and Perception, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 20 Years of Awards Winners: Society of Illustrators/ Collaboration: Artists and Architects, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Of the Land’s Bounty: Gardens Woods and Meadows/ 200 Years of Freemasonry/ The Mayor’s House: Gracie Mansion and Other Dwellings, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Tales of Christmas Past/ New York in Aerial Views, 1981 December, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - George Washington in NY State/ Sailing Ships in Dutch Prints/ FDR: A Centennial Celebration, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Manhattan Observed: 14 Photographers Look at New York, 1982 May (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Grand Central Terminal/ The Female Touch, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Oom Pah Pah: The Great American Band, 1982 July (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Oom Pah Pah: The Great American Band, 1982 July (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - A Collector’s Sampler: Library Accessions 1980-1982/ Greetings of the Year/ Sampler of American Advertising From the Landauer Collection (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - A Heritage to Remember: The Black Experience in New York, 1983 January (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - A Celebration: American Landscape Painting, 1983 February (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Washington Irving Bicentennial/ A Child’s World, 1983 March (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The World of Tiffany, 1983 May (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - A Bridge Opens to Brooklyn/ Artists’ Views of Central Park/ A Celebration of Opera, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Struggle for a Continent: Francis Parkman’s “France and England in North America”, 1983 October (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Firefighting on Parade, 1983 October (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Themes of New York: Prints by Meyerowitz and Bernstein/ Lights, Camera, Action: New York’s Silent Film Studios, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - The Library of John Pintard/ From Shanties to Skyscrapers, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - New York and the China Trade, 1984 February (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - New York and the China Trade, 1984 February (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Sons of St. Patrick: Irish and Irish Organizations in New York/ The Adirondacks/ Centennial Tribute to the Grolier Club, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Five New York Families/ Treasures of Manuscript Americana, 1984 May (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Visions of Liberty, 1984 June (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lost in the Shuffle: Playing Cards and Board Games/ Her Voice Was Heard: Women and Politics in America, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - A Pageant of Heraldry in Britain and America/ Baroness Hyde de Neuville Sketches of America/ Lurid Literature, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Centuries of Childhood/ Karol Kozlowski, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Audubon’s Birds of North America: The Original Watercolors, 1985 April (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Audubon’s Birds of North America: The Original Watercolors, 1985 April (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Chicago and New York/ Metropolis in Mourning: Ulysses S. Grant 1822-1885, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - To the Publick: NY in Broadsides/ Statue of Liberty Centennial Celebration, 1985 September (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Artist in Residence: North Country Art of Frederic Remington/ The Great Fire of 1835: Sesquicentennial Anniversary, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Niagara: Two Centuries of Changing Attitudes, 1697-1901, 1986 January (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Prized Prints/ P.T. Barnum, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - James Henry Cafferty, 1819-1869/ Liberty’s Legacy: New York’s Ethnic Festivals/ Storied Shores: Lake George in Legend and History, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Made for New York: Antique Toys from the Collection of Lawrence Scripps Wilkinson, 1986 October (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Portrait of Livingston Manor, 1686-1850/ Pleasure of Your Company: Parties and Balls in New York City, 1986 November (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - New York Bestiary: Pets and Pests of the Metropolis/ Wagstaff Collection of American Silver, 1987 March (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The Hudson River and the Highlands: Photographs by Robert Glenn Ketchum, 1987 April (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Jackie Robinson: An American Journey, 1987 April (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Strong on Music: The New York Music Scene, 1836-1850, 1987 June (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution, 1987 September (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Government by Choice: Inventing the U.S. Constitution, 1987 September (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Portraits of Power: Paintings from the Collection of the N.Y. Chamber of Commerce and Industry/ Ex Libris Rufus King, 1987 September (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Jasper Cropsey: Artist and Architect, 1987 October (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Blizzard of ‘88/ Bellows, Bobbins, and Butter Churns: Keeping House in 19th Century America, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Francis William Edmonds: American Master in the Dutch Tradition/ Artistic Houses: Lavish Interiors of 19th Century New York, 1988 April (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - The Rise and Fall of New York: Building and Unbuilding Manhattan/ The Invisible Surface: Paper and the Printing Arts In Early America, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Putting New York on the Map/ Arnold Newman: Five Decades, 1988 September (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hard Cider and Hot Air: The Selling of the President/ Celebrating the Holidays in Old New York, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - The Belknap Collection of Silver and Portraits, 1988 November (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Burr McIntosh: Polite Society 1900-1910/ Revisiting the World’s Fair of 1939, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - George Washington in New York, 1989 April (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Irving Browning: City of Contrasts, 1989 June (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Cased Images: the 150th Anniversary of Photography/ An American Sampler: Folk Art from the Shelburne Museum, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Nicolino Calyo: 19th Century Views of New York/ Below the Line: Living Poor in America, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Paris 1889: American Artists at the Universal Exposition, 1990 September (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Thomas Jefferson Bryan Gallery: Changing Attributions, 1990 September (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Charles Gilbert Hine: Impressions of a City, 1990 October (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - The Luman Reed Gallery, 1990 November (Box 19, Folder 8)